# Jennifer Lindsey

Irvine, CA, 92618 | Email | Portfolio | LinkedIn

#### SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Art & Design and a dedication to life-long learning. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Experience in collaborating to create and deliver materials that are accessible to all audiences. Enthusiastic, creative and detail-oriented with a willingness to learn new technologies.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, React, CSS, HTML5, jQuery, Bootstrap, Material Back-End: NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, JSON, GraphQL, JWT

Tools: Git, GitHub, NPM, VSCode, Heroku, Chrome Dev Tools

Other: Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator, Agile

Familiar with: CSS animations, RESTful APIs, SPA using React, ¡Query, PWA

#### **PROJECTS**

## State of the Art

**GitHub** 

# **Application**

- Full stack Application designed to allow museums and similar institutions to add, search, and edit location of artwork. By signing up through the app, the user can then add title, artist, date, medium, style and location of their institution's artwork.
- Role: creating log-in functionality, build the dataset, styling w/ CSS & Bootstrap, creating Handlebars framework.

## **One Stop Print Shop**

GitHub link App link

- Full stack MERN Application using GraphQL API designed to allow users to sign-up & log-in to an E-Commerce site that uses Stripe API for checkout. By signing up through the app, the user can add products to their cart, and if user goes off-line the cart contents will persist.
- Role: create Front End components & pages, functionality of creating Global State, shopping cart functionality, Stripe API functionality, CSS, Bootstrap.

## **Brewed Force**

GitHub Application

- Website designed to unite the beer minded traveler with new breweries and beers in new cities. By entering a city into the search feature, the user will be met with a list of breweries in that city. We used the Open Brewery API & Punk API.
- Role: CSS for application & JavaScript for local storage, JavaScript/ HTML / CSS / Material Design Lite

#### ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Critical thinking and analysis Attention to detail

Presentations and public speaking

Excellent communication skills

Ability to work autonomously or with a team
Able to adapt content for diverse audiences

Aesthetic/design conscious for UI & UX

lesearch Creativ

Problem-solving and decision-making Adaptable & excited to learn new technologie

## **EDUCATION**

**Certificate** - Software Engineering

Apr 2021 - Sep 2021

Vanderbilt University

**Bootcamp Certificate**: 24-week intensive MERN software development program focused on gaining technical programming/coding skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, NodeJS, JSON, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, GraphQL, ReactJS.

BA - Art History and French University of Texas, Arlington, TX

MA - Art History

Courtauld Institute of Art, University of London, London, England, London

## **EXPERIENCE**

Museum Educator | Kimbell Art Museum

2019 - 2020

Work collaboratively with fellow museum educators to create and present interactive gallery & studio art programs. Modeled critical thinking to connect all audiences to works of art within the permanent collection.

Art History Professor | Southern New Hampshire University 2013 -

Taught Modern Art, Art History and Art Appreciation courses in an online environment, engaging students through discussion board and article reflections, & journals.

Yoga/Meditation Instructor | Mindful Pose

2012 - Present

Teaching hatha yoga, mindful flow, yoga nidra and meditation classes in corporate and private sessions. Providing a safe & supportive environment for all levels of practitioners

Visual Thinking & Strategies | Boston MFA

Spring 2012

Observed teachers in the classroom to facilitate discussions of visual art to increase student engagement, performance, and enjoyment of learning. Scored, transcribed essays and input data into database for research of teaching critical thinking skills in a classroom setting.

Coordinator

2010 - 2011

Hope Cottage

Designed a state-wide marketing campaign for non-profit, mobile media ad. Created & implemented Client Management Database for reporting. Developed, wrote, and edited database manual for staff.